<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[There and back again]]></title><description><![CDATA[There and back again]]></description><link>https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io</link><image><url>https://aboutme.imgix.net/background/users/t/e/r/terencecreamer_1473115180_14.jpg</url><title>There and back again</title><link>https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 18:57:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Automated Testing Using Jenkins on AWS]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="admonitionblock caution">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-caution" title="Caution"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The following assumptions are made: You are familiar with Amazon Web Services enough to understand <a href="#anchor-1">the first step in the Jenkins Master on AWS section</a>.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_jenkins_master_on_aws">Jenkins Master on AWS</h3>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_configure_your_aws_account">Configure your AWS account</h5>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
I like to keep AWS from using the default for options when setting up my EC2s. It keeps me aware of the layout of my infrastructure without creating too much cruft.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div id="anchor-1" class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Configure a Virtual Private Cloud with an Internet Gateway and a Public Subnet. Ensure your Public Subnet is configured to auto-assign IP addresses. It&#8217;s optional but recommended to also create an Elastic IP to associate with your Jenkins EC2 (either via Network Interface or directly with the EC2 instance).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Create an EC2 instance within the infrastructure created in step #1. I used a <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/marketplace/pp/B00O7WM7QW">Centos 7 Amazon Machine Instance (AMI) entitled "CentOS 7 (x86_64) - with Updates HVM)"</a>. This AMI is free-tier eligible, and a t2.micro is large enough to run a Jenkins Master server. Obviously, scale up if need be. No need to assign an IAM role to this server. TODO is storage actually required?</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock tip">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-tip" title="Tip"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Note the key pair used to access the instance. We will use this key pair later to allow the Jenkins Master to access the agents. I named my key pair "jenkins" 'cause I&#8217;m creative like that :-) .
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The EC2 instance created in step #2 will be referred to as the "Jenkins Master" going forward. Technically, this makes sense because really all this server does is run the Jenkins Master process.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock caution">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-caution" title="Caution"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Be sure the Route Table associated with your VPC has an entry for the Internet Gateway. This does not happen automatically when associating an Internet Gateway to a VPC.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_install_jenkins">Install Jenkins</h5>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Log into the Jenkins Master EC2 instance using your jenkins key pair.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Follow the instructions to <a href="https://jenkins.io/download/">install Jenkins</a>. If using the same Centos 7 AMI I did, <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Installing+Jenkins+on+Red+Hat+distributions">Red Hat Distributions Install instructions here</a>.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For me, installing Jenkins (latest LTS) boiled down to these commands, then logging in using the password when first visiting Jenkins Master at port 8080:</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre>sudo yum install java
sudo yum install wget
sudo wget -O /etc/yum.repos.d/jenkins.repo http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/redhat-stable/jenkins.repo
sudo rpm --import https://jenkins-ci.org/redhat/jenkins-ci.org.key
sudo yum install jenkins
sudo service jenkins start
sudo cat /var/lib/jenkins/secrets/initialAdminPassword #To get the initial admin password</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Be sure a version of Jenkins greater than 2 (major version) installs. So 2.32.1-1.1 works. We will use Jenkins Plugins that require a Jenkins major version of greater than or equal to 2.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock tip">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-tip" title="Tip"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Jenkins provides a nice startup interface for installing plugins, but all these plugins can be installed from the Jenkin&#8217;s Update Center. Since we don&#8217;t need to install many plugins for this tutorial we will move past this (click the X in the top right), but it&#8217;s useful to know what plugins are offered and what plugins are "suggested".
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_jenkins_master_creates_agents_on_aws">Jenkins Master creates Agents on AWS</h3>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_install_and_configure_the_amazon_ec2_plugin">Install and Configure the Amazon EC2 Plugin</h5>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
I will keep this brief by not attempting to describe Jenkins interface in too much detail. That being said, use the second bar from the top (not the first black one, but the light blue one below that) to orient yourself; It will dynamically populate as you navigate through Jenkins.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>From the home screen go to "Manage Jenkins" &gt; "Manage Plugins". Install the <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Amazon+EC2+Plugin">Amazon EC2 plugin</a>. It&#8217;s dependencies will install with it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Navigate to "Manage Jenkins" &gt; "Configure System". The Amazon EC2 plugin added a "Cloud" section. Click "Add a new cloud" &gt; "Amazon EC2". Several configuration settings will appear; Basically now we populate these settings!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Follow the instructions below to <a href="#anchor-2">Connect to your Amazon EC2 via a Jenkins IAM Role</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click the "Add" button next to AMIs setting. This will give us some AMI settings to populate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Choose an AMI to use. Populate corresponding settings about the AMI and how you would like it spun up. These settings include: AMI ID, Instance Type, EBS Optimized, Availability Zone, Security Group Names, AMI Type, and Use Spot Instance. For me, I opted for the same instance type for my Build Agents as my Jenkins Master,  <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/marketplace/pp/B00O7WM7QW">a Centos 7 (AMI) called "CentOS 7 (x86_64) - with Updates HVM)"</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For remote user, check what the default user is one should log in with when SSHing into the AMI. For me, it&#8217;s "centos". TODO does Remote FS Root &amp; Root command prefix &amp; Remote SSH port &amp; Labels matter?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Use the Init Script setting to configure the AMI you choose to handle Jenkins, adjust security as necessary, and add the RSA public key to the authorized key file on the server. This last step will allow the Jenkins Master to log into the Build Agent spun up as needed. Since the AMI I chose was very bare bones my Init Script looked like this:</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">echo "=== 0 of 2 | Jenkins Master Init Script ==="
echo "=== 1 of 2 | Configuring Build Agent ==="
jenkinsRSApub="[Your key pair's public key without brackets in quotes]"
echo $jenkinsRSApub &gt;&gt; /home/centos/.ssh/authorized_keys
setenforce 0
echo "=== 2 of 2 | Installing Required Software ==="
sudo yum update --assumeyes
sudo yum install wget --assumeyes
sudo yum install scp --assumeyes
sudo yum install java-1.8.0-openjdk --assumeyes
sudo yum install git --assumeyes</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>8.Note the "Advanced" button on the far-right at the bottom of the AMI settings. This button can be difficult to see depending on how the settings populate. Click it to see some additional AMI configurations. I set the "Number of Executors" and "Instance Cap" to 1 to keep several pipelines from running at once on a Build Agent and restrict Jenkins from spinning up several Build Agents to process jobs, added the Subnet ID for my VPC, added my ARN for my IAM instance profile, and checked "Connect By SSH Process".
9.Now you are ready to test that <a href="#anchor-3">Jenkins Master creates Build Agents using EC2s as needed</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="anchor-2">Connect to your Amazon EC2 via a Jenkins IAM Role</h5>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Fortunately, the <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Amazon+EC2+Plugin">Amazon EC2 plugin</a> has an "IAM setup" section. There, it provides the JSON to properly configure the Jenkins IAM Policy the Jenkins IAM Role would use. I added the iam:PassRole permission to my policy. TODO Find out if things work the same without the iam:PassRole permission in the policy.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Navigate to your Identity and Access Management (IAM) section of your AWS account and create a Jenkins Policy using the JSON provided plus iam:PassRole.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Create a Jenkins Role that uses the Jenkins Policy. Save the following details when they are made available to you: "Access Key ID", "Secret Access Key", and "IAM Role to Use" (an Amazon Resource Name (i.e. ARN, example: "arn:aws:iam::123456789012:role/MyIAMRoleName") )</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Once you have these details navigate back to Jenkins &gt; Manage Jenkins &gt; Configure System, Cloud section. For the "Amazon EC2 Credentials" setting click the "Add" dropdown and select "Amazon EC2". A popup will appear with credential configuration settings. For "Kind" select "AWS Credentials". Populate the "Access Key ID", "Secret Access Key", and "IAM Role To Use". "IAM Role To Use" needs to be an ARN. Then complete the form by clicking "Add"; Not having all the fields filled out does not cause an issue. TODO might not need the "IAM Role To Use" ARN if Jenkins user already exists.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Copy the private key pair (my "jenkins" key pair) into the "EC2 Key Pair&#8217;s Private Key" setting.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Select a Region to use. It has to be a Region the key pair from step #5 is registered to.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click "Test Connection". It should say "Success" in small black text or display an error in bold red text.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="anchor-3">Test Jenkins Master Creates Build Agents Using EC2s As Needed</h5>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>On the Jenkins Homepage, navigate to "New Item".</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You will be asked to create a name for this item, then select what type of item it is. In my case at this point I can only select "Freestyle Project" and press "OK".
3.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_jenkins_master_uses_agents_to_process_pipelines_on_aws">Jenkins Master uses Agents to Process Pipelines on AWS</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Configure Amazon EC2 Plugin</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_build_a_pipeline_using_a_jenkinsfile">Build a Pipeline Using a Jenkinsfile</h3>

</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_configure_jenkins_to_trigger_pipelines_from_github_activity">Configure Jenkins to Trigger Pipelines from Github Activity</h3>

</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_going_forward">Going Forward</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>TODO:
.build agents for specific repos
.Automatically kick off build when PR is opened into master</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io/2017/01/20/Automated-Testing-Using-Jenkins-on-AWS.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io/2017/01/20/Automated-Testing-Using-Jenkins-on-AWS.html</guid><category><![CDATA[AWS]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Jenkins]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Testing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Automated Testing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Installation]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Configuration]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Terry Creamer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Setting up Neo4j for Spatial Queries]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="admonitionblock tip">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-tip" title="Tip"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
<a href="http://legis-graph.github.io/legis-graph-spatial/">Here&#8217;s an example application</a> issuing spatial queries to Neo4j and the <a href="https://neo4j.com/blog/geospatial-indexing-us-congress-neo4j/">associated blog post</a>.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock caution">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-caution" title="Caution"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The following assumptions are made: You have a version of <a href="https://neo4j.com/download/other-releases/">Neo4j 3.x</a> installed. You are familiar with <a href="http://neo4j.com/docs/developer-manual/current/get-started/#cypher-getting-started">the Cypher Query Language ("Ascii art for graph databases")</a>. All work is performed through the Neo4j browser interface.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_installation_of_neo4j_spatial">Installation of neo4j-spatial</h3>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Create a plugins folder within your Neo4j database location. In my case this was
<code>/Users/trycrmr/Documents/Neo4j/3.0.3/spatialPlaytime/plugins</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Download the appropriate version of the <a href="https://github.com/neo4j-contrib/spatial">neo4j-spatial</a> plugin for your 3.x version of Neo4j. This is likely a zipped up .jar file.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>unzip the .jar file and put it in the plugins directory created earlier. The full path to my neo4j-spatial .jar file is <code>/Users/trycrmr/Documents/Neo4j/3.0.3/spatialPlaytime/plugins/neo4j-spatial-0.19-neo4j-3.0.3-server-plugin.jar</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Restart your Neo4j server</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Issuing the following cypher query to Neo4j lists the procedures available to you now that the neo4j-spatial plugin is installed: <code>CALL spatial.procedures</code></p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: There is no documentation for the these procedures yet, but insights can be drawn (such as what parameters can be passed to the procedures) from <a href="https://github.com/neo4j-contrib/spatial/blob/master/src/main/java/org/neo4j/gis/spatial/procedures/SpatialProcedures.java">the code</a> at this time. For example, the parameters for the <code>spatial.withinDistance</code> are listed in the code below (hint: <code>@Name</code>)</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code class="language-java" data-lang="java">    @Procedure("spatial.withinDistance")
    @PerformsWrites // TODO FIX
    public Stream&lt;NodeDistanceResult&gt; findGeometriesWithinDistance(
            @Name("layerName") String name,
            @Name("coordinate") Object coordinate,
            @Name("distanceInKm") double distanceInKm) {

        Layer layer = getLayerOrThrow(name);
        return GeoPipeline
                .startNearestNeighborLatLonSearch(layer, toCoordinate(coordinate), distanceInKm)
                .sort(DISTANCE)
                .stream().map(r -&gt; {
                    double distance = r.hasProperty(DISTANCE) ? ((Number) r.getProperty(DISTANCE)).doubleValue() : -1;
                    return new NodeDistanceResult(r.getGeomNode(), distance);
                });
    }</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_importing_a_map_layer">Importing a Map Layer</h3>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Find the mapping data (i.e. Shapefiles) of the area you would like your graph database to map. In this case we will use <a href="http://www.naturalearthdata.com/downloads/10m-cultural-vectors/10m-admin-0-countries/">Shapefiles provided by Natural Earth, supported by the North American Cartographic Information Society</a>.</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p>Of note: The download will contain several files. We will need all of them.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Two of the procedures neo4j-spatial provides (as of October 2016) are <code>addLayer(name :: STRING?, type :: STRING?, encoderConfig :: STRING?)</code> and <code>importShapefileToLayer(layerName :: STRING?, uri :: STRING?)</code>. addLayer takes three arguments: The name to use for the layer, the type of layer it is, and how it will be encoded. importShapefileToLayer takes two arguments: The name of the layer to import the Shapefile to and a URI of where the Shapefiles are located. Validate these procedures exists then:</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p>Call the addLayer procedure. In my case the cypher statement was <code>CALL spatial.addLayer("countryBordersWKT","WKT","")</code>. How it is encoded can be left blank in this instance.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Place the folder containing all the files downloaded in step 1 in Neo4j&#8217;s /bin directory. In my case the location of the directory was <code>/Applications/Neo4j Community Edition 2.app/Contents/Resources/app/bin</code>. The procedure will look for the folder of Shapefiles in the /bin directory.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Call the procedure importShapefileToLayer passing the name of the layer and the location of the .shp file within the Shapefiles folder relative to the /bin directory. In my case the call was <code>CALL spatial.importShapefileToLayer("countryBordersWKT","ne_10m_admin_0_countries/ne_10m_admin_0_countries.shp")</code>. This creates the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R-tree">R-tree</a> structure within Neo4j database, which could be thought of as the mathematical backbone of the spatial capabilities neo4j-spatial facilitates creating and curating.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If the procedures ran without errors your map layer was successfully imported! You can validate this by finding the "spatial root" node and expanding the other nodes it&#8217;s related to.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre>MATCH (n:ReferenceNode) RETURN n LIMIT 1</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Maps can vary given what countries are recognized by the organizations creating the map in conjunction with when they were created. A pretty obvious example would be a map created in the 1600s would not include the United States.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_finding_a_point_within_a_country">Finding a Point Within a Country</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>--1. Now that we have a map layer consisting of the world&#8217;s countries we can find what country a point resides in. To make our Cypher statements more intuitive add a "Country" label to all nodes referencing the RTREE:</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre>MATCH ()-[:RTREE_REFERENCE]-&gt;(c)
SET c:Country
RETURN c.NAME ORDER BY c.NAME</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>--2. The withinDistance procedure will give us the nearest node to a point. Naturally, if a point is within a country, that country is the nearest country to that point. Passing what map layer withinDistance should use, the latitude and longitude as a map (i.e. key value pairs within curly brackets), and the radius around our point we would like to perform our search will provide use all the country nodes within one meter of this point.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre>CALL spatial.withinDistance('countryBordersWKT',
{latitude: 33.93, longitude: -118.40}, 0.001) YIELD node as c
RETURN c.NAME</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As the latitude and longitude for Los Angeles was used this query should return "United States".</p>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock caution">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-caution" title="Caution"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Keep an eye out for negative latitudes and longitudes. <a href="https://mynasadata.larc.nasa.gov/latitudelongitude-finder/">Here&#8217;s a handy map for validating your querying the area of the world you think you are.</a>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_search_for_the_distance_between_nodes_in_the_same_country">Search for the distance between nodes in the same country</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>--1. Create a node with a latitude and longitude. The following query will also create a <code>WITHIN</code> relationship between that node and the country it resides in. This will be useful if one would like to query for points only within a specific country.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre>CREATE (l:Location {latitude: 43.65, longitude: -79.38, name: "Toronto"})
WITH l
CALL spatial.withinDistance('countryBordersWKT',
{latitude: l.latitude, longitude: l.longitude}, 0.001) YIELD node as c
CREATE (l)-[:WITHIN]-&gt;(c)
RETURN *</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>--2. Validate you can perform a query that calculates the distance between two location nodes.</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre>MATCH (a:Location {name: "Baltimore"}),(b:Location {name: "Los Angeles"})
RETURN a.name, b.name, toInt(distance(point(a),point(b)) / 1000) as distance;</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This query will provide the distance in kilometers between two locations which are in the same country:</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre>MATCH (a:Location {name: "Baltimore"}),(b:Location),(a)-[:WITHIN]-&gt;(c:Country)
WHERE NOT a.name = b.name AND (b)-[:WITHIN]-&gt;(c)
RETURN a.name, b.name, c.NAME, toInt(distance(point(a),point(b)) / 1000) as distanceInKM ORDER BY distanceInKM</pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock important">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-important" title="Important"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
To be continued&#8230;&#8203;
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">TODO</dt>
<dd>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Create test data to prove spatial capabilities</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Issue a spatial cypher query on test data</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Incorporate into larger dataset</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Prove on a larger dataset</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">stuff</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Add layer</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Add nodes to layer</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p>Bulk add nodes to layer</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>issue query using findGeometriesWithinDistance (or withinDistance)</p>
<div class="dlist">
<dl>
<dt class="hdlist1">NOTES</dt>
<dd>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/89064528">0313 - Recommend Restaurants Near Me: Introduction to Neo4j Spatial</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26560023/how-do-i-create-a-spacial-index-in-neo4j-using-only-cypher" class="bare">http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26560023/how-do-i-create-a-spacial-index-in-neo4j-using-only-cypher</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/37219809/neo4j-3-0-0-spatial-in-cypher" class="bare">http://stackoverflow.com/questions/37219809/neo4j-3-0-0-spatial-in-cypher</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.lyonwj.com/2016/08/09/neo4j-spatial-procedures-congressional-boundaries/" class="bare">http://www.lyonwj.com/2016/08/09/neo4j-spatial-procedures-congressional-boundaries/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://hiu.state.gov/data/data.aspx" class="bare">https://hiu.state.gov/data/data.aspx</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://trac.osgeo.org/gdal/wiki/DownloadingGdalBinaries" class="bare">http://trac.osgeo.org/gdal/wiki/DownloadingGdalBinaries</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://gis.stackexchange.com/questions/7339/converting-shapefiles-to-text-ascii-files" class="bare">http://gis.stackexchange.com/questions/7339/converting-shapefiles-to-text-ascii-files</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://gis.stackexchange.com/questions/54870/how-to-convert-a-shapefile-to-wkt" class="bare">http://gis.stackexchange.com/questions/54870/how-to-convert-a-shapefile-to-wkt</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://gist.asciidoctor.org/?dropbox-14493611%2Fcypher_spatial.adoc#_spatial_procedures" class="bare">http://gist.asciidoctor.org/?dropbox-14493611%2Fcypher_spatial.adoc#_spatial_procedures</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.naturalearthdata.com/downloads/10m-cultural-vectors/10m-admin-0-countries/" class="bare">http://www.naturalearthdata.com/downloads/10m-cultural-vectors/10m-admin-0-countries/</a></p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>GeoJSON of ^ <a href="https://github.com/AshKyd/geojson-regions/tree/master/data/countries/ne_10m_admin_0_countries.geo.json" class="bare">https://github.com/AshKyd/geojson-regions/tree/master/data/countries/ne_10m_admin_0_countries.geo.json</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>ESRI countries <a href="https://www.arcgis.com/home/item.html?id=3864c63872d84aec91933618e3815dd2" class="bare">https://www.arcgis.com/home/item.html?id=3864c63872d84aec91933618e3815dd2</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Geodetic_System" class="bare">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Geodetic_System</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>WGS countries <a href="http://www.gadm.org/country" class="bare">http://www.gadm.org/country</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>more up to date William Lyons post on using the user defined procedures in neo4j-spatial <a href="http://www.lyonwj.com/2016/08/09/neo4j-spatial-procedures-congressional-boundaries/" class="bare">http://www.lyonwj.com/2016/08/09/neo4j-spatial-procedures-congressional-boundaries/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>neo4j-spatial guy <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/2954199/william-lyon?tab=profile" class="bare">http://stackoverflow.com/users/2954199/william-lyon?tab=profile</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/38231044/how-do-i-create-a-simplepointlayer-in-neo4j-spatial" class="bare">http://stackoverflow.com/questions/38231044/how-do-i-create-a-simplepointlayer-in-neo4j-spatial</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://neo4j-contrib.github.io/spatial/" class="bare">http://neo4j-contrib.github.io/spatial/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://techslides.com/list-of-countries-and-capitals" class="bare">http://techslides.com/list-of-countries-and-capitals</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://neo4j.com/docs/developer-manual/current/cypher/#_spherical_distance_using_the_haversin_function" class="bare">https://neo4j.com/docs/developer-manual/current/cypher/#_spherical_distance_using_the_haversin_function</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io/2016/10/08/Setting-up-Neo4j-for-Spatial-Queries.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io/2016/10/08/Setting-up-Neo4j-for-Spatial-Queries.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Neo4j]]></category><category><![CDATA[ neo4j-spatial]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Installation]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Configuration]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Terry Creamer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Installing Squid on CentOS 7]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_installing_a_href_http_www_squid_cache_org_squid_a_on_centos_7">Installing <a href="http://www.squid-cache.org/">Squid</a> on CentOS 7</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="admonitionblock caution">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-caution" title="Caution"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
The following assumptions are made: You are able to edit text files in the terminal and yum is your package manager.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock warning">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-warning" title="Warning"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
These instructions are for standing up a simple, unsecure Squid instance. Secure appropriately for your context.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Installation</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>yum install squid</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p>Installs to /etc/squid</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Configuration</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Optional, remove comments from squid.conf, <code>grep -Eiv '(<sup>#|</sup>$)' /etc/squid/squid.conf &gt; /etc/squid/squid.conf.new</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Set <code>http_port</code> from <code>3128</code> to <code>80 accel allow-direct</code>. This will allow Squid to proxy all HTTP traffic.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Add the following rules. They will allow Squid to process and reply to any http traffic it receives:</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p><code>http_access allow all</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>http_reply_access allow all</code></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock tip">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-tip" title="Tip"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
For all the ways Squid can be configured, take advantage of <a href="http://wiki.squid-cache.org/">Squid&#8217;s Wiki</a> and their <a href="http://www.squid-cache.org/Doc/">website&#8217;s documentation</a> (particularly their <a href="http://www.squid-cache.org/Doc/config/">list of Squid configs</a>).
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Starting</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Enable Squid with systemctl: <code>systemctl enable squid</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Start Squid: <code>systemctl start squid</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Validate Squid is running by checking the processes <code>ps -ax | grep "squid"</code></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Changes to the squid.conf are implemented by restarting Squid ( <code>systemctl restart squid</code> )
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock tip">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-tip" title="Tip"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Firefox 47.x can be configured to point all traffic to a proxy server under Preferences &gt; Advanced &gt; Network &gt; Connection. Can be useful for testing Squid.
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_optional_configurations">Optional Configurations</h3>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Caching</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Uncomment <code>cache_dir ufs /var/spool/squid 100 16 256</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Comment out all the <code>refresh_pattern</code> configs except <code>refresh_pattern .</code></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock tip">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-tip" title="Tip"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
Validate Squid is properly proxying requests by tailing the access logs on the Squid server <code>tail -f /var/logs/squid/access.log</code>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="admonitionblock note">
<table>
<tr>
<td class="icon">
<i class="fa icon-note" title="Note"></i>
</td>
<td class="content">
If testing using Firefox 47.x by disabling the local browser web cache by changing the amount of space allocated to the local web cache to 0mb at Preferences &gt; Advanced &gt; Network &gt; Cached Web Content
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<div class="title">Load Balancer</div>
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Add the following configs to squid.conf, inserting the appropriate IP or Public DNS as necessary:</p>
<div class="olist loweralpha">
<ol class="loweralpha" type="a">
<li>
<p><code>http_port 80 accel act-as-origin [insert primary destination server IP or Public DNS]</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>cache_peer [insert primary destination server IP or Public DNS] 80 0 no-query originserver round-robin</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>cache_peer [insert secondary destination server IP or Public DNS] parent 80 0 no-query originserver round-robin</code></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Test by navigating to Squid. You should see content from one of the two destination servers.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io/2016/10/04/Installing-Squid-on-CentOS-7.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://trycrmr.github.io/hubpress.io/2016/10/04/Installing-Squid-on-CentOS-7.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Squid]]></category><category><![CDATA[ CentOS 7]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Installation]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Configuration]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Terry Creamer]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>